Wendell Clark Bennett Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
Wendell Clark Bennett Archives
1940-1953
ANTAR.000003
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
20
The archives of Wendell Clark Bennett, accumulated through his time at Yale.
Bennett, Wendell Clark
Biographical Sketch
Wendell Bennett (b.1905, d.1953) was a research associate in anthropology from 1945 to 1953. Bennett's major contribution to the anthropology collections were in South American archaeology, particularly the Huari material from Peru and other collections from Columbia and Ecuador that are curated by the Museum.
Education
- B.A. University of Chicago, 1927
- M.A. University of Chicago, 1929
- Ph.D. University of Chicago, 1930
Affiliations
- Research staff at Bishop Museum, Hawaii (1928-1929)
- Assistant Curator of South American
Archaeology at AMNH (1931-1938)
- Associate Professor of Anthropology at the University of Wisconsin (1938-1940)
- Professor of Anthropology at Yale University
Description of the Material
The archives of Wendell Bennet include correspondence, research material and photgraphs from North and South America as well as lecture notes and lantern slides.
Peru; Bolivia; Ecuador; Columbia; Maps; Photographs; Manuscript materials; Research notes; Yale Peabody Museum; Yale University
- Maps, 1940-1953; Series I
  - Linguistic Maps. Linguistic Maps of South America., 1940-1953; 033869
- Photographs, 1940-1953; Series II
  - American Indian Pictures., 033932
  - Argentina. Calchaqui., 033820
  - Bolivia. Part 1 of 2: Cochabamba, Arani, Colcapirhua, Iluri, Cayacayani, Coati Island, Titicaca Island, Southeast and South Shore Lake Titicaca, Sillustani, Tiahuanaco, Chiripa, Paco, Quehuava, Pariti, Cascachi Temple, Lucurmata, Intja, Yayescpuente, Copacabana, Chocupercas, Riberalta., 033818.001
  - Bolivia. Part 2 of 2: Cochabamba, Arani, Colcapirhua, Iluri, Cayacayani, Coati Island, Titicaca Island, Southeast and South Shore Lake Titicaca, Sillustani, Tiahuanaco, Chiripa, Paco, Quehuava, Pariti, Cascachi Temple, Lucurmata, Intja, Yayescpuente, Copacabana, Chocupercas, Riberalta., 033818.002
  - Bolivian Indians., 033903
  - Brazil. Marajo., 033821
  - Cayamarca Style., 033912
  - Chicama Ceramics., 033921
  - Chile. Chuquicamata, La Serena, Tocopilla., 033822
  - Collections., 033924
  - Colombia. Part 1 of 2: San Agustin, Tierra dentro, Putumayo, Narino, Upper Cauca, Quimbaya, Sinu, Chibcha, Santa Marta, Tairona, Baranquilla., 033816.001
  - Colombia. Part 2 of 2: San Agustin, Tierra dentro, Putumayo, Narino, Upper Cauca, Quimbaya, Sinu, Chibcha, Santa Marta, Tairona, Baranquilla., 033816.002
  - Cuzco Style., 033920
  - Cuzco., 033929
  - Ecuador. Cuenca, Inga Pircha, Ibarra, East Ecuador, Jivaros, Rio Napo., 033819
  - Embroidery., 033906
  - Epigonal., 033911
  - Guatemala., 033826
  - Interlocky., 033908
  - Lambazique Ceramics., 033923
  - Magellan., 033928
  - Metal., 033922
  - Mexico., 033825
  - Miscellaneous., 033830
  - Modern Indians., 033915
  - Nazca., 033918
  - North Coast., 033925
  - North Highlands., 033917
  - Painting., 033931
  - Panama., 033823
  - Paracas., 033919
  - Peru. Bennett Photographs (Part 1 of 3): Bronze, Gold, Textiles, Indians, Corn, South Coast, Nazca, Pacheco, Palpa, Ica, Chincha, Paracas, Mummy, Pachacamac, Para-Monga, Huarmey, Viru, Pucara, Cuzvo, Saccahuaman, Ollantaitambo, Machu Picchu, Lambayeque, Tucume, Gayoso, Chongoyape, Casma, Nepena, Chao, Chan Chan, Trujillo, Moche, Las Delicias, Chicama, El Brujo, Pata de Burro, Pucuche, Salmanca, Playa, Chavin, Mochica, Late Chimu., 033817.001
  - Peru. Bennett Photographs (Part 2 of 3): Bronze, Gold, Textiles, Indians, Corn, South Coast, Nazca, Pacheco, Palpa, Ica, Chincha, Paracas, Mummy, Pachacamac, Para-Monga, Huarmey, Viru, Pucara, Cuzvo, Saccahuaman, Ollantaitambo, Machu Picchu, Lambayeque, Tucume, Gayoso, Chongoyape, Casma, Nepena, Chao, Chan Chan, Trujillo, Moche, Las Delicias, Chicama, El Brujo, Pata de Burro, Pucuche, Salmanca, Playa, Chavin, Mochica, Late Chimu., 033817.002
  - Peru. Bennett Photographs (Part 3 of 3): Bronze, Gold, Textiles, Indians, Corn, South Coast, Nazca, Pacheco, Palpa, Ica, Chincha, Paracas, Mummy, Pachacamac, Para-Monga, Huarmey, Viru, Pucara, Cuzvo, Saccahuaman, Ollantaitambo, Machu Picchu, Lambayeque, Tucume, Gayoso, Chongoyape, Casma, Nepena, Chao, Chan Chan, Trujillo, Moche, Las Delicias, Chicama, El Brujo, Pata de Burro, Pucuche, Salmanca, Playa, Chavin, Mochica, Late Chimu., 033817.003
  - Photo Albums., 033827
  - Tapestry., 033914
  - Textiles., 033930
  - Tiahuanaco Air Views., 033909
  - Tiahuanaco Ruins., 033926
  - Tiahuanaco Sculpture., 033916
  - Titicaca Sites., 033927
  - Twill., 033907
  - Venezuela., 033824
  - Viru Ceramics., 033913
  - Wari., 033910
- Manuscript Materials, 1940-1953; Series III
  - Bennett Manuscript Plates and Figures. Box 1 of 3 boxes., 033889.001
  - Bennett Manuscript Plates and Figures. Box 2 of 3 boxes., 033889.002
  - Bennett Manuscript Plates and Figures. Box 3 of 3 boxes., 033889.003
  - Hawaii Manuscript. Hawaii Manuscript and notes., 1930; 033873
  - South American publications., 035912
- Research Material, 1940-1953; Series IV
  - Andes Ethnology. Split over two archive boxes., 033845
  - Argentina. N.W. Argentina, La Paya., 033894
  - Chaco Ethnology., 033844
  - Chile. Research notes on the Atacamenta., 033893
  - Colombia. Research notes on Colombia., 033899
  - Field Notes., 033883
  - Hawaii. Kauai Place Names., 033895
  - Hopi. Research notes on the Hopi., 033892
  - Iriquois. Research notes on the Iriquois., 033891
  - Miscellaneous., 033896
  - Miscellaneous. Tarahumara MS; Middle America-Costa Rica; Mexico (Simpson); Columbia Diary, 1941; Chibcha; Santa Marta; Quimbaya; Tierra Aduetio; San Augustine; Narino; Ecuador Cuenca; Colombia, Preuss, K.J, 1929; Nambiquara; Aymara Texts; Bolivian Labor; Aymara; Middle America; Tarahumara-Linguistics; Bennett, et al. Argentine; Tarahumara., 033933
  - Miscellaneous. Miscellaneous research material, 57 folders., 033946
  - Oneida. Research notes on the Oneida., 033890
  - Plates., 033947
  - South American Archaeology., 033835
  - South American Ethnology. 2 boxes., 033834
  - South American Tropical Rainforest., 033836
- Research Bibliographies, 1940-1953; Series V
  - Argentina. Bibliography. Part 1., 033841.001
  - Argentina. Bibliography. Part 2., 033841.002
  - Bolivia., 033935
  - Colombia., 033839
  - Ecuador., 033838
  - General Anthropology., 033848
  - Miscellaneous. Miscellaneous bibliographies, some duplicates, 14 folders., 033936
  - North America., 033849
  - Paraguay., 033843
  - Peru-Bolivia. Archaeology-Ethnology, by Author., 033846
  - Peru-Bolivia. Archaeology, by Subject., 033847
  - South America & Mexico., 033837
  - South American Ethnology. 4 of 5 boxes of South American Ethnology Bibliography. Boxes 1, 2, 3 and 4., 033833.001
  - South American Ethnology. 1 of 5 boxes of South American Ethnology Bibliography. Box 5., 033833.002
  - Uraguay., 033842
  - Venezuela., 033840
  - Viru., 033850
  - Wari., 033851
- Teaching Materials, 1940-1953; Series VI
  - American Indian., 033856
  - Anthropology 100. 3 folders., 033940
  - Anthropology 34., 033881
  - Archaeology., 033941
  - European Prehistory., 033855
  - General Atnthropolgy II., 033854
  - General Atnthropolgy I., 033853
  - Miscellaneous. 13 folders., 033942
  - Miscellaneous. 26 folders., 033944
  - Modern Latin America II., 033859
  - Modern Latin America I., 033858
  - North American Ethnographic. MacKenzie, Northwest Coast, Plains, Southeast, Eastern Woodlands, Plateau., 033857
  - Sociology 106., 033879
  - Sociology 110., 033939
  - Sociology 15. 2 folders., 033937
  - Sociology 27., 033943
  - Sociology 46., 033938
- Miscellaneous, 1940-1953; Series VII
  - Exchange of Students and Research Personell. 4 folders., 033888
  - Illustrations. Pottery Illustrations, Notes and Plates., 033870
  - Illustrations. Illustrations of Sculptures., 033871
  - Joint Committe on Latin American Studies. 4 binders, notes removed from binders., 033886
  - Miscellaneous. Glass slides, film rolls, etc., 033862
  - Miscellaneous. Film roll, Drawing of La Mata Mound Section, Venezuela, and pottery samples., 033905
  - Miscellaneous. Duplicate papers/reports; Conference of Bolivian Indians; Kirchoff, P. 1931; Roop, W.F. Watercraft in Amazonia; Peru Metals., 033934
  - Newspaper Clippings. Miscellaneous folder of newspaper clippings., 033898
  - Nordenskiold Manuscript., 033887
  - Personnel File. North and South America., 033861
  - Reports to the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs. Miscellaneous Reports to the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs., 033902
  - Social Science Research Council. Notes on the Social Science Research Council, 21 folders., 033945
- Lantern Slides, 1940-1953; Series VIII
  - Lantern Slides. Tiahuanaco, Highlands., 033875
  - Lantern Slides. Inca, Chiripa, Pucara., 033876
  - Lantern Slides. Maps, Scenes, Coast Periods, Casma, Recuay-Charin., 033877
  - Lantern Slides. Textiles, Metals., 033878